<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jason Fitzgerald</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jason Fitzgerald</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How Far Does the Apple Fall From the Tree?</title>
      <link>/2019/09/how-far-does-the-apple-fall/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/how-far-does-the-apple-fall/</guid>
      <description>Introduction During the 4th of July I started to have this question: which of my ancestors served in the Revolutionary War? I began my search for records of proof of service on FamilySearch and Ancestry. As I was clicking up and down my family tree, I wondered if there was a way to read the family history (GEDCOM) files in R. After an in-depth search, I couldn’t find anyone with a good GEDCOM parser that would turn it into CSV format in R (however, a similar project was recently begun; https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal Sentiments</title>
      <link>/2019/02/journal-sentiments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/journal-sentiments/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I have a great time writing in my journal. It is fun to reread my journal from time to time and reminisce about old memories and see how I have changed. Since I have already been doing a lot with text-analysis, I started to think what would doing a simple sentiment analysis look on my journal?
 Reading in My Journal It took a little bit to find the right way to read in my journal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building A Map For Henry Schein</title>
      <link>/2019/01/henry-schein/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/henry-schein/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I had the great opportunity to do an internship with Henry Schein the previous summer and was able to build a connection with the lead Data Scientist there. They donated some of the data for this project to our school’s data science society, where I was appointed as team lead.
The data has been changed from the original for privacy, but this is what we where able to provide for Henry Schein.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Skills Do Employers Look For In Data Scientists vs. Business Analysts</title>
      <link>/2017/12/data-scientists-vs-business-analysts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/data-scientists-vs-business-analysts/</guid>
      <description>In this analysis, I am going to be looking at the most commonly used words in job postings related to Data Science and Business Intelligence. I am wanting to see what skills are common between the two, and where they differ. While talking with others about what else they would like to see in this analysis is where those jobs are located, so I will make an attempt at doing that as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/2015/07/hello-r-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/07/hello-r-markdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>